



Web Developer

Enthusiastic and Ambitious **web developer** with **6+ years' experience** to contribute to **team success** through hard work with excellent organizational skills. welcoming **challenging projects** and enjoying working with all sorts of personalities and Eager to work with personnel in all areas of company to help boost profits and improve **opportunities**.

SNAPSHOT OF ME

- Created entire applications and patchable connectors for use with cloud-based platforms.
- Worked closely from planning stages to deployment to deliver on-target projects.
- Enabled CI/CD Pipeline for Auto-Deployments from GitLab to multiple servers including AWS (EC2) and
 Running Test cases for many projects.
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple business.
- Reviewed scalability, **performance and load balancing** of each application with million records.

SKILLS (Proficient to Basic)

Front-End Development:

Languages: JavaScript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, SCSS

Framework: Vue.js (v3+ with Bulma/TailwindCSS & Pinia/VueX, Vite Config), Angular (v8+ with NgRx)

Libraries & Toolkit: jQuery, NPM/Yarn, Bootstrap (v4+), Gulp, Babel

Test Framework: Jest

Back-End Development:

Languages: C#, PHP, Bash Scripting, GraphQL

Framework: (MVC and Restful APIs) .Net6, Express - Node.js, Phalcon, Magento, Shopify

Libraries & Toolkit: NuGet, TPL (Task Parallel Library) **Test Framework & Tool:** xUnit, SonarQube, Snyk

DevOps:

CI/CD: Gitlab Deployments Automation

Version Control & Issue Tracker: GitHub, Gitlab, Jira

Data Management and Analytics:

Messaging Queue and Data Ingestion: Kafka (streaming)

Analytics: Splunk

Databases: MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, Firebase(Realtime Database)

Server and Cloud Services:

Web Servers: Nginx, Apache

Cloud Services & Platforms: PCF, AWS (EC2 and Amplify), Digital Ocean, Laravel Forge, Server Pilot, Hostinger,

GoDaddy

<u>Conceptual Knowledge:</u> DSA, Sharding, Load Balancer, API Gateway, Hadoop HDFS, DNS Resolver, System Designing, Cassandra Partitioning, CAP Theorem

EDUCATION

- BE(ECE) from Dr. Mahalingam college of engineering and technology in 2017 with 84%.
- +2(HSS) from Kurinji Higher Secondary school in 2012 with 92.25%.

TECH SKILLS & TEAM SPIRITS IN A NUTSHELL

- Proactively took ownership and full responsibility for end-to-end feature development.
- Addressed and unblocked challenges faced by the team to ensure smooth progress.
- Volunteered for automating modules to enhance process efficiency.
- Refactored backend systems using TPL (Task Parallel Library) in .NET to improve performance and maintainability.
- Improved frontend JavaScript code to enhance user experience and application responsiveness.
- Actively shared knowledge and provided training to team members.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dell Technologies

Dell Principal Software Engineer 12/2021~Present

URLs: www.dell.com

Clients: Dell

Technologies: HTML5, CSS (Less), JavaScript(Es6)/jQuery, C# (.Net), Cassandra(.CQL), xUnit, Jest

Tools: Gitlab CI/CD, Jira ,Snyk, SonarQube, Kafka, splunk

Role: Full Stack Developer

Current Key Roles and Responsibilities:

- **Developer Support**: Assist developers in overcoming challenges related to project architecture, technical challenges, and test case problems.
- Feature Development: Develop and upgrade features using the above mentioned stack.
- Code Review: Review and approve merge requests to ensure code quality and adherence to standards
- Production Deployment: Oversee and execute production deployments to ensure smooth rollouts.
- Code Optimization: Optimize and enhance code for performance, maintainability, and robustness.
- **Problem Solving:** Tackle and complete challenging tasks that the team is unable to resolve.
- Migration and Security: Handle migration projects and fix any identified vulnerabilities.

Nexii Labs Inc(Contractor).

06/2020~11/2021

Dell (Ecom) Senior Software Engineer 01/2021~11/2021

URLs: www.dell.com

Clients: Dell

Technologies: HTML5, CSS (Less), JavaScript/jQuery, C# (.Net6), Cassandra (.CQL)

Thoughtfocus (Saas Apps) Senior Software Engineer 06/2020~12/2020

URLs: www.bayviewassetmanagement.com

Clients: Bayview Asset Management.

Technologies: Vue.js, Keno UI, CSS3, SCSS, GraphQI.

Key Achievements: Made Dynamic Query Builder search for GraphQl.

Shanki Systems India Pvt Ltd.

02/2017~06/2020

SSO (Single Sign On) Software Engineer 04/2018~06/2018

URLs:www.accounts.vettrix.com, **Clients:** Medium size B2B clients.

Technologies: Phalcon, Vue Js (2+), Bootstrap4, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3.

Key Achievements:

• Developed with complete security option such as Hash Password, 2FA, JWT, IP whitelisting, Google login.

ERP Solutions Software Engineer 04/2019~06/2020

URLs: www.sales.vettrix.com_www.invoice.vettrix.com

Clients: Medium size B2B clients.

Technologies: Phalcon, Vue.is, Bootstrap4, MySQL, CSS3, SCSS

Key Achievements:

Migrated a whole application from monolithic to microservice architecture.

- Deployed application after successful load testing with million records for multiple users.
- Developed multiple reusable components (Mostly for CRUD Operations and Excel bulk upload).
- Bulk Import options for all the master data to make user migration easier and to consume time.

Admin Tool Software Engineer 01/2019~03/2019

URLs: www. admin.vettrix.com. **Clients:** Medium size B2B clients.

Technologies: Phalcon, Vue.js, Bootstrap4, MySQL, CSS3, SCSS

Key Achievements:

- Implemented concept of each user can handle multiple organization with multiple warehouses.
- Slack Integration, Razor pay payment integration, Google drive integration.

WHAT MAKES ME TICK

- Exploring New Technologies / Solving challenging task (Leet Code and Hacker Rank in Recent times),
- Pencil art and craft work,
- Yoga, Dance,
- Puzzle games

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Languages: Tamil, English.

DOB: 08/11/1996Nationality: Indian.

MY COMMITMENT

I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge.